Guide to the Burdette Keeland Architectural Papers
University of Houston Libraries
- Planning Commission, 1913-1993
  - Houston: Major Thoroughfare Plan, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 49)
  - Houston: Water Districts Map, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 50)
- Travels, 1962-1995
  Veteran travelers, Keeland and his wife Margie made annual trips to destinations around the world. His files contain records of trips to Europe, Asia and Africa during the 1980s and 1990s.
  - Trips to Take, 1980s-1990s (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Africa Trip, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 2-3)
  - India Trip, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 4-7)
  - Paris, Amsterdam trip, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Danube Trip, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 9-11)
  - Saintes, France Trip, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Greece Trip, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 13-14)
  - Sicily, London, France, Spain Trip, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 15-22)
  - Mexico - Photographs, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - New Orleans - Photographs, 1970s (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Italy - Photographs, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 25-26)
  - Rome - Photographs, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Florence - Photographs, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 28-30)
  - Milan - Photographs, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - Switzerland - Photographs, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - New York City - Photographs, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - New York City - Photographs, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - South America - Photographs, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - Chicago - Photographs, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 36)
  - Washington, D.C. - Photographs, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 37)
  - Vienna, Danube Trip - Photographs, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 38)
  - Warsaw - Photographs, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 39)
  - Saintes, France Trip - Photographs, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 40)
  - Greece - Photographs, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 41)
  - Sicily - Photographs, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 42)
  - England - Photographs, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 43)
  - Ronchamps - Photographs, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 44)
  - Boulder, CO - Photographs, 1990s (Box 16, Folder 45)
  - Boston, MA - Photographs, undated (Box 16, Folder 46)
  - Mart, TX - Photographs, undated (Box 16, Folder 47)
  - Miscellaneous Travel Photographs, undated (Box 16, Folder 48)
- Cemeteries, 1940s-1990s
  This section contains Keeland’s collection of materials about cemeteries, including reference materials, photographs, and his materials for a book on the subject that was never published.
  - Places, 1985-1995 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Student Sketches, 1990s (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Reference, 1990-1995 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Articles, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Cemetery Guides, undated (Box 17, Folder 5-9)
  - Forest Park, Keeland, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Clippings of Keeland Articles, 1994-1995 (Box 17, Folder 11-12)
  - Texas Monthly Article, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Letters and Cards, 1987-1995 (Box 17, Folder 14-17)
  - Notes for Book, 1990s (Box 17, Folder 18-19)
  - Expenses for Book, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Graphics for Book, approximately 1988 (Box 17, Folder 21-29)
  - Keeland Tombstone Designs, 1992-1995 (Box 17, Folder 30-31)
  - Keeland Tomb Designs for AG&M, 1996-1997 (Box 17, Folder 32-42)
  - Speeches and Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 17, Folder 43)
  - Idea File, undated (Box 17, Folder 44)
  - S.C.I. Annual Report, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 45)
  - Clippings, 1980s-1990s (Box 17, Folder 46-49)
  - Photographs, 1940s-1990s (Box 17, Folder 50-57)
  - Photographs, Japan (winter), 1996 (Box 17, Folder 58)
  - Photographs, Japan (spring), 1995 (Box 17, Folder 59)
  - Photographs, Somerville, TX, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 60)
  - Photographs, Oaxaca, Mexico, 1990s (Box 17, Folder 61-62)
- Memorabilia, 1944-1950
  Memorabilia include personal effects from Keeland’s army service (1944–1946), although there are several personal items and others from his professional career. They are contained in one small box and three oversize flat boxes.
  - Wooden Sandals from Japan (Box 18, Item 1)
  - Shell casings (Box 19, Item 1)
  - Military buttons (Box 19, Item 2)
  - Texas Driver’s License (Box 19, Item 3)
  - Dining Utensils (Box 19, Item 4)
  - Office address stamp (Box 19, Item 5)
  - Scott Field Decals (Box 20, Item 1)
  - Identification Card, Japan, 1946 (Box 20, Item 2)
  - Tourist Map, Japan, 1946 (Box 20, Item 3)
  - Army Furlough Ticket, 1945 (Box 20, Item 4)
  - Telegram, 1945 (Box 20, Item 5)
  - Immunization Records (2) (Box 20, Item 6)
  - Army Meal Tickets (2) (Box 20, Item 7)
  - Small American Flag (Box 20, Item 8)
  - Military Cap (Box 20, Item 9)
  - Army uniform patches, badges, and ticket stubs (6 sleeves) (Box 20, Item 10)
  - Army Discharge Papers (1 folder), 1946 (Box 20, Item 11)
  - Framed picture, Houston National Bank Building (Box 20, Item 12)
  - Framed diploma, University of Houston, 1950 (Box 20, Item 13)
  - Used leather billfold (Box 20, Item 14)
  - Nameplate, “B.W. Keeland Co.” (Keeland's Father) (Box 20, Item 15)
  - Folding ruler (Box 20, Item 16)
  - Yank (includes an article on Houston), August 3, 1945 (Box 21, Item 1)
  - Stars and Stripes, August 7, 1946 (Box 21, Item 2)
  - Customs Declaration, July 1946 (Box 21, Item 3)
  - Clippings of Keeland cartoons (Box 21, Item 4)
  - Newsletters for Keeland’s transport ships (3 issues), 1945-1946 (Box 21, Item 5)
  - TAABloid, army base newspaper (23 issues), December 1945–July 1946 (Box 21, Item 6)
- Reference Materials, 1905-2000
  This series contains magazines, exhibition catalogs, and oversized clippings that Keeland saved for reference. Subjects of interest include art, architecture, World War II, and Frank Sinatra. Several of the publications from the 1950s contain features on Keeland’s buildings. They are contained in seven oversize flat boxes.
  - Sam C. Holliday, “The Tao of Thor” (unpublished essay), 1968 (Box 22, Item 1)
  - Catalog & Price List, Gulf Coast Negative Service, undated (Box 22, Item 2)
  - Houston Metropolitan, July 1992 (Box 22, Item 3)
  - Houston Metropolitan, July 1993 (Box 22, Item 4)
  - Houston Metropolitan, August, 1993 (Box 22, Item 5)
  - Progressive Architecture, May, 1994 (Box 22, Item 6)
  - Progressive Architecture, June 1994 (Box 22, Item 7)
  - Sallyport, June/July 1993 (Box 22, Item 8)
  - JAE, September 1997 (Box 22, Item 9)
  - Texas Architecture Catalog, Dallas Museum of Fine Arts, 1952 (Box 23, Item 1)
  - Extra (UH Alumni publication), 1959 (Box 23, Item 2)
  - Parade Plan Book, Meyerland Parade of Homes, 1955 (Box 23, Item 3)
  - Arts & Architecture, Winchell Studio, April 1955 (Box 23, Item 4)
  - Arts & Architecture, Meyerland Parade of Homes, October 1955 (Box 23, Item 5)
  - Architectural Forum - reprint, December 1955 (Box 23, Item 6)
  - Architectural Forum, Winchell Studio, October 1954 (Box 23, Item 7)
  - House and Home, Meyerland Parade of Homes, September 1955 (Box 23, Item 8)
  - Show, April 1965 (Box 24, Item 1)
  - Life, July 6, 1905 (Box 24, Item 2)
  - Life, August 5, 1940 (Box 24, Item 3)
  - Life, December 24, 1965 (Box 24, Item 4)
  - Life, December 23, 1966 (Box 24, Item 5)
  - Life, December 27, 1968 (Box 24, Item 6)
  - Life, June 25, 1971 (Box 24, Item 7)
  - Life, December 17, 1971 (Box 24, Item 8)
  - Life, December 29, 1972 (Box 24, Item 9)
  - Life, December 1974 (Box 24, Item 10)
  - Life, Spring-Summer 1985 (Box 24, Item 11)
  - Picasso, Contemporary Arts Museum, 1955 (Box 25, Item 1)
  - John Marin, Mark Tobey, Morris Graves, Contemporary Arts Museum, 1956 (Box 25, Item 2)
  - 10 Years of Houston Architecture, Contemporary Arts Museum, 1959 (Box 25, Item 3)
  - Houston Works, Rice Design Alliance, 1997 (Box 25, Item 4)
  - Best Laid Plans, Rice Design Alliance, 1994 (Box 25, Item 5)
  - Burdette Keeland, Jr. Associates firm brochure (Box 25, Item 6)
  - Portfolio, letters for TSA Educators Award, 1993 (Box 25, Item 7)
  - Blueprint Ball invitation materials, 1998 (Box 25, Item 8)
  - College of Architecture Building Dedication program, 1986 (Box 25, Item 9)
  - Composition Book, UH College of Architecture, 1989-1990 (Box 25, Item 10)
  - Open Plan, The History of the College of Architecture, University of Houston, 1945-1995 (Box 25, Item 11)
  - Varve, The Journal of the University of Houston, College of Architecture, 1990–1991 (Box 25, Item 12)
  - Yale Constructs, 1999 (Box 26, Item 1)
  - Skyline, March 1983 (Box 26, Item 2)
  - Cite, August 1982 (Box 26, Item 3)
  - Cite, Winter 1984 (Box 26, Item 4)
  - Cite, Fall 1987 (Box 26, Item 5)
  - Cite, Fall 1990 (Box 26, Item 6)
  - Cite, Fall 1991 (Box 26, Item 7)
  - Cite, Winter 1997-1998 (Box 26, Item 8)
  - Cite, Winter 1999 (Box 26, Item 9)
  - Cite, Summer 1999 (Box 26, Item 10)
  - Articles and Clippings - Alvar Aalto, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Articles and Clippings - Craig Ellwood, 1958 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Articles and Clippings - Buckminster Fuller, 1960s (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Articles and Clippings - Walter Gropius, 1968 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Articles and Clippings - Philip Johnson, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Articles and Clippings - Louis Kahn, 1960s (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Articles and Clippings - Robert Kennedy, 1968 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Articles and Clippings - Mies van der Rohe, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Articles and Clippings - Carl Milles, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Articles and Clippings - Morris firm, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Articles and Clippings - Ralph Rapson, 1999 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Articles and Clippings - Paul Rudolph, 1960s (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Articles and Clippings - Stanford White, 1960s (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Articles and Clippings - Magruder Wingfield, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Articles and Clippings - Architecture, General, 1950s-1990s (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Articles and Clippings - Architecture, Images, 1960s-1980s (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Articles and Clippings - Art, General, 1950s-1990s (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Articles and Clippings - Art, Images, 1960s-1980s (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Articles and Clippings - Celebrities, Images, 1960s-1980s (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Articles and Clippings - People, Images, 1960s-1980s (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Articles and Clippings - Popular Culture, General, 1960s (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Articles and Clippings - Texas Fashion, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Articles and Clippings - Travel, General, 1960s-1980s (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - The Architect covers, 1927-1928 (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - Music Album Posters, 1960s (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - Menus, 1969, 1975 (Box 27, Folder 26)
  - Houston General Study Plan for 1990, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Office Forms and Title Blocks, 1990s (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Notes for 2000 Keeland Exhibition, 1999–2000 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Hobby Center proposals, 1997 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Enron Building Expansion, 1998 (Box 28, Folder 5-8)
  - Desk Calendars, 1962, 1967, 1969, 1980, 1981, 1982, 1983, 1984, 1985, 1986 (Box 28, Item 1)
  - Notepad labled "Burdette Keeland" (Box 28, Item 2)
- Oversized photographs and artwork, 1935-1990s
  Large oversized artwork and photographs of Keeland’s architecture are stored in flat-file drawers. Smaller such materials, however, may be found in this oversized box.
  - Unidentified Spanish Colonial building, 1935 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Ronchamps photo, 1966 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Keeland with Paul Rudolph photo, 1981 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Keeland, Todd, Wingfield Photo, 1990s (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Meyerland Parade of Homes House, 1955 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Harry Holmes Shopping Center, 1960s, 1970s (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Spring Branch Savings & Loan proposal, 1960s (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Essex-Houck Building, 1960s, 1990s (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Negatives of Artwork, 1980s (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Photographs of Clippings, 1970s (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Keeland Residence, Ferndale St., Remodel, 1986 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Virginia Street Townhouses, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Shields Office Building, 1955 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Malco Oil Offices, New Mexico, 1956 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Williams Beach House, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Kipling Apartments, 1953 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Arnold House, 1955 (Box 29, Folder 17-18)
- Cemeteries - Oversized Materials, 1990s
  Keeland’s passion for cemeteries and tombstones appears in materials elsewhere in the collection. This group contains oversized materials, including photographs, photocopies and clippings related to cemeteries.
  - Color Photocopies, 1990s (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Photographs, 1990s (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Materials for Keeland artwork on cemeteries (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1990s (Box 30, Folder 4)
- Art Cards
  Keeland and his friends often exchanged large greeting cards and announcements collaged from newspaper and magazine images. This group is composed of oversized cards received by Keeland on birthdays and other occasions. Many are from Bill Shields, an artist who was Keeland’s high-school classmate. Shields was one of Keeland’s early clients before he moved to San Francisco. Also included are a group of color prints of artwork from Shields from the late 1990s.
  - Sixteen handmade greeting cards, various media on cardboard (Box 31, Item 1)
  - Twenty-five color prints of artwork by Bill Shields (Box 31, Item 2)
  - Two decorative drink coasters by Bob Englebach (Box 31, Item 3)
- Miscellaneous Oversized Materials, 1947-2004
  This group includes various oversized materials related to Keeland’s professional career. The 2004 poster was received from the UH College of Architecture while the collection was in processing. It concerns an event for the College of Architecture’s new Burdette Keeland building, named for Keeland after his death.
  - Burdette Keeland poster, 2004 (Box 32, Ovs item 1)
  - Wall board from 2000 Exhibition (Box 32, Ovs item 2)
  - 40 Proof Poster - artwork and proofs, 1994 (Box 32, Ovs item 3)
  - Keeland sketch for house interior (mounted on board), 1950s (Box 32, Ovs item 4)
  - Keeland and unidentified group, Photograph (mounted on board), 1977 (Box 32, Ovs item 5)
  - Plates and film negatives for Keeland office brochure, 1966 (Box 32, Ovs item 6)
  - “Yale” metal sign (white letters on blue background), undated (Box 32, Ovs item 7)
  - Keeland cartoon of Philip Johnson and Howard Barnstone, 1947 (Box 33, Ovs item 1)
  - “Calvert Future,” Keeland sketch of town planning project (reproduction of rolled original), mid 1960s (Box 33, Ovs item 2)
  - Photograph, Taylor Green Weekend House, 1963 (Box 33, Ovs item 3)
  - Keeland sketches on tracing paper, tombstones, undated (Box 33, Ovs item 4)
  - Sketches by Keeland, Michael Graves, Stanley Tigerman, and Anderson Todd (Box 33, Ovs item 5)
  - Copy of Proclamation for Burdette Keeland Day, 1991 (Box 33, Ovs item 6)
  - Lecture Poster, UH College of Architecture, 1990 (Box 33, Ovs item 7)
  - Lecture poster, Rice Design Alliance, undated (Box 33, Ovs item 8)
  - Collage of Keeland with important architects, undated (Box 33, Ovs item 9)
  - Copies of materials on Keeland’s buildings for 2000 exhibition (Box 33, Ovs item 10)
  - Oversized clippings of Keeland cemetery articles (Box 33, Ovs item 11)
  - Prospectus, Hermitage Museum, Russia, 1999 (Box 33, Ovs item 12)
  - Zero, student publication, UH College of Architecture, 1968 (Box 33, Ovs item 13)
- Oversized Architectural Renderings, 1953-1983
  This group contains oversized prints of renderings and sketches for some of Keeland’s architectural projects.
  - Winchell Apartment & Studio, 1953 (Box 34, Ovs item 1)
  - 2721 Kipling Apartments, 1953 (Box 34, Ovs item 2)
  - Shields Office Building, 1955 (Box 34, Ovs item 3)
  - Arnold Residence Addition, 1955 (Box 34, Ovs item 4)
  - Port au Prince, Haiti Building, 1956 (Box 34, Ovs item 5)
  - Spring Branch Savings & Loan, 1957 (Box 34, Ovs item 6)
  - Barnstone-Keeland Building, W. Capitol St., 1964 (Box 34, Ovs item 7)
  - Virginia Street Townhouses - Negatives, 1975 (Box 34, Ovs item 8)
  - 4141 Greenbriar Building - Prints, 1983 (Box 34, Ovs item 9)
- Keeland Exhibition, February 10-March 3, 2000
  Shortly before his death, the University of Houston’s College of Architecture honored Keeland with a retrospective exhibition. Open from February 10 through March 3, 2000 in the college’s gallery, the show explored his career through numerous images of his work. Keeland assisted the organizers with preparation of the exhibition. This series contains many of the images from the exhibition, each mounted on a foam-board panel.
  - Keeland Exhibition Images, February 10-March 3, 2000 (Box 35-40)
- Architectural Projects - Drawings
  This series contains Keeland’s architectural drawings. They fall into four categories: Studies and Preliminary Drawings, Working Drawings, Prints, and Presentation Drawings. All are large format and are stored in flat files in oversized folders. Some projects contain examples of more than one category of drawings.
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 1)
    - Keeland Residence #1 - Working Drawings, 1950 (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 1, Item 1)
    - Keeland Residence #1, Additions - Working Drawings, 1954 (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 1, Item 2)
    - Strange Residence - Working Drawings, 1950 (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 1, Item 3)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 2)
    - Lander Residence - Working Drawings, 1952 (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 2, Item 1)
    - Dr. Fitch Offices - Working Drawings, 1952 (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 2, Item 2)
    - William Bridges Residence - Preliminary Drawings, 1952 (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 2, Item 3)
  - 2721 Kipling Apartments - Working Drawings (fragile), Presentation Drawing, 1953 (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 3)
  - Winchell Studio and Apartment - Working Drawings, Presentation Drawing, 1953 (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 4)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 5)
    - Fitch Apartments - Working Drawings, 1953 (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 5, Item 1)
    - 2400 Kipling Apartments - Working Drawings, 1953 (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 5, Item 2)
    - Lander Office Building - Working Drawings, 1953 (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 5, Item 3)
    - Carousel Shop - Working Drawings, 1954 (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 5, Item 4)
  - Menking Residence - Working Drawings, Presentation Drawing, 1955 (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 6)
  - Fast Car Wash - Working Drawings, Presentation Drawing, 1954-1956 (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 7)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 8)
    - Gross Apartments - Working Drawings, 1954 (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 8, Item 1)
    - Moody Residence - Working Drawings, 1955 (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 8, Item 2)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 9)
    - Arnold Residence Addition - Working Drawings, Presentation Drawing, 1955 (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 9, Item 1)
    - Baker Residence - Working Drawings, Presentation Drawing, 1955 (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 9, Item 2)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 10)
    - Shields Office Building - Preliminary Drawings, 1955 (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 10, Item 1)
    - Houck Office Building - Preliminary Drawings, Presentation Drawing, 1955 (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 10, Item 2)
  - Shields Office Building - Working Drawings, 1955-1956 (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 11)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 12)
    - Meyerland Parade of Homes House - Working Drawings, Presentation Drawing, 1955 (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 12, Item 1)
    - Holmes Shopping Center, Lake Jackson - Working Drawings, Presentation Drawing, 1955 (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 12, Item 2)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 13)
    - Lister Residence Renovation - Working Drawings, 1956 (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 13, Item 1)
    - Port au Prince, Haiti Building - Working Drawings, Presentation Drawing, 1956 (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 13, Item 2)
    - Horne Residence - Working Drawings, 1956 (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 13, Item 3)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 14)
    - Malco Asphalt & Refining Building - Working Drawings, Presentation Drawing, 1956 (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 14, Item 1)
    - Wells Design Addition - Working Drawings, 1956 (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 14, Item 2)
  - Miscellaneous Presentation Drawings, 1950s (Drawer 1, Ovs folder 15)
  - King Residence Project - Working Drawings, 1956 (Drawer 2, Ovs folder 16)
  - Spring Branch Savings & Loan - Working Drawings, 1957 (Drawer 2, Ovs folder 17)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 2, Ovs folder 18)
    - Prutzman Residence #3 - Working Drawings, Presentation Drawings, 1956-1957 (Drawer 2, Ovs folder 18, Item 1)
    - King Residence Guest House - Working Drawings, 1957 (Drawer 2, Ovs folder 18, Item 2)
    - Moser Residence - Working Drawings, 1957-1958 (Drawer 2, Ovs folder 18, Item 3)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 2, Ovs folder 19)
    - Houck Office Building, Richmond Ave. - Working Drawings, undated (Drawer 2, Ovs folder 19, Item 1)
    - Houck Office Building, Weslayan St. - Working Drawings, 1957 (Drawer 2, Ovs folder 19, Item 2)
    - Houck Office Building Addition - Working Drawings, approximately 1961 (Drawer 2, Ovs folder 19, Item 3)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 2, Ovs folder 20)
    - Peterson Residence Addition - Working Drawings, 1957-1958 (Drawer 2, Ovs folder 20, Item 1)
    - Port Commission Remodeling Project - Preliminary Drawings, Presentation Drawing, 1958 (Drawer 2, Ovs folder 20, Item 2)
    - Holmes Shopping Center - Working Drawings, 1958 (Drawer 2, Ovs folder 20, Item 3)
  - Houck Residence - Working Drawings, 1958-1959 (Drawer 2, Ovs folder 21)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 2, Ovs folder 22)
    - Shields Residence - Working Drawings, 1958 (Drawer 2, Ovs folder 22, Item 1)
    - Arnold Apartments - Working Drawings, Presentation Drawing, 1958 (Drawer 2, Ovs folder 22, Item 2)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 2, Ovs folder 23)
    - Japhet Residence - Working Drawings, 1958 (Drawer 2, Ovs folder 23, Item 1)
    - B.W. Keeland, Sr., Bay House - Working Drawings, undated (approximately 1958) (Drawer 2, Ovs folder 23, Item 2)
    - Mengden Residence - Working Drawings, 1959 (Drawer 2, Ovs folder 23, Item 3)
  - Read Apartments - Preliminary Drawings, 1959 (Drawer 2, Ovs folder 24)
  - Read Apartments - Working Drawings, 1959 (Drawer 3, Ovs folder 25)
  - Keeland Sr. Office Building Addition - Preliminary Drawings, Working Drawings, approximately 1959 (Drawer 3, Ovs folder 26)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 3, Ovs folder 27)
    - Memorial Bend Club - Working Drawings, 1959 (Drawer 3, Ovs folder 27, Item 1)
    - Spring Branch Savings & Loan Addition - Working Drawings, Presentation Drawing, 1959 (Drawer 3, Ovs folder 27, Item 2)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 3, Ovs folder 28)
    - Gulf Service Station - Preliminary Drawings, Presentation Drawing, approximately 1958 (Drawer 3, Ovs folder 28, Item 1)
    - Beaumont Road Volunteer Fire Station - Working Drawings, undated (Drawer 3, Ovs folder 28, Item 2)
    - Kuldell Office Building - Preliminary Drawings, Presentation Drawing, undated (Drawer 3, Ovs folder 28, Item 3)
    - Sunset Boulevard Offices Addition - Preliminary Drawings, undated (Drawer 3, Ovs folder 28, Item 4)
  - Essex-Houck Building - Preliminary Drawings, Working Drawings, Presentation Drawings, 1961 (Drawer 3, Ovs folder 29)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 3, Ovs folder 30)
    - Pan Am Oil Co. Building Additions (Hines) - Preliminary Drawings, Presentation Drawing, 1961 (Drawer 3, Ovs folder 30, Item 1)
    - Keeland Residence Additions - Working Drawings, 1961 (Drawer 3, Ovs folder 30, Item 2)
  - King Center Shopping Center - Working Drawings, 1961 (Drawer 3, Ovs folder 31)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 3, Ovs folder 32)
    - Holmes Shopping Center, Willowbend Blvd. - Preliminary Drawings, Working Drawings, 1961 (Drawer 3, Ovs folder 32, Item 1)
    - Pan Am Oil Co. Additions - Working Drawings, 1962 (Drawer 3, Ovs folder 32, Item 2)
  - Architectural Drawings (Drawer 3, Ovs folder 33)
    - B.W. Keeland, Sr., Bay House - Working Drawings, 1962 (Drawer 3, Ovs folder 33, Item 1)
    - Carter Residence - Working Drawings, Presentation Drawing, 1962 (Drawer 3, Ovs folder 33, Item 2)